Finding aid to the Emily Hale Papers CA.MS.00344
Smith College Archives
Emily Hale Papers
1915-1990
Smith College Archives
Hale, Emily, 1891-1969
CA.MS.00344
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Professor of Speech. Collection contains biographical materials, correspondence, and photographs.
Biographical / Historical
Emily Hale was born on October 27, 1891 to Reverend Edward and Emily (Milliken) Hale. She attended a number of preparatory schools in Cambridge and Boston, and eventually graduated from Miss Porter's School in Farmington, CT. She went on to work in the Speech/Drama departments of a number of colleges in the country, including Simmons College (1916-1921), Milwaukee-Downer College (1921-1928), Scripps College (1932-1934), and Abbott Academy (late 1950s). Hale came to Smith College in 1936 and worked as an Assistant Professor in the Department of Spoken English until 1942. After leaving Northampton, she taught at numerous secondary schools for girls in New York, Maine and Massachusetts. During her lifetime, Hale was an active member of the Unitarian Church, and of the Northampton Historical Society and Northampton Area Council of Churches. She volunteered at the Sophia Smith Collection and was active in the League of Women Voters. On October 12, 1969, in Concord, MA, Emily Hale passed away at the age of 79.
Scope and Contents
The Emily Hale papers contain biographical materials, correspondence, photographs, and newspaper clippings covering Hale's career as a faculty member at Smith College and other aspects of her personal life.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials in the Emily Hale papers came to the College Archives from a number of sources.
Hale, Emily, 1891-1969
- Biographical Material, 1936-90 (Box 840, Folder 1)
- Abbott Academy, 1950-57 (Box 840, Folder 2)
- Certificates, 1953 (Box 840, Folder 3)
- Christmas Cards, 1949-54 (Box 840, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Perkins, Edith B., 1954-55 (Box 840, Folder 5)
- Concord Academy, 1946 (Box 840, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1924-59 (Box 840, Folder 7)
- Dramatic Appearances, 1915-60 (Box 840, Folder 8)
- Dramatic Appearances - "My Fair Lady", 1968 (Box 840, Folder 9)
- Examinations, 1957 (Box 840, Folder 10)
- Harvard University, 1957 (Box 840, Folder 11)
- Lectures, 1930-42 (Box 840, Folder 12)
- Lecture Notes, undated (Box 840, Folder 13)
- Milwaukee-Downer College, 1922-30 (Box 840, Folder 14)
- Photographs, 1893-61 (Box 840, Folder 15)
- Publications, 1928-51 (Box 840, Folder 16)
- Recitals, 1933 (Box 840, Folder 17)
- Scripps College, 1932-34 (Box 840, Folder 18)
- Scripps College - Hay Fever, 1931-34 (Box 840, Folder 19)
- Simmons College, 1918 (Box 840, Folder 20)
- Simmons College, 1937-63 (Box 840, Folder 21)
- University of Wisconsin, 1941 (Box 840, Folder 22)